Who Owns the Spice
Whoever owns the world
Imperial Diary 10191 Comment 3
Imperial diary, year 10191, third comment.
The Battle of Arrakis Shocked the World
The battle for Arrakis took everyone by surprise.
No witnesses
There were no witnesses.
The Harkonnen&#39;s actions were
The Harkonnen operation was perpetrated
At night without warning or declaration of war
overnight without warning or declaration of war.
By morning, the Atreides were wiped out.
By morning, the Atreides were no more.
All died in the long night
All died in the dark.
And the Emperor...
And the Emperor said...
Silence
Nothing.
My father was never the same from that night on.
Since that night my father has not been the same.
Me too
Nor have I.
His sadness and haggardness broke my heart
His inaction is difficult for me to accept.
Because I know he loves Lord Leto Atreides like a son.
For I know he loved Duke Leto Atreides, like a son
But my father was always trapped by power
But my father has always been guided by the calculus of power.
This is not the first time
This would not be the first time the
The dirty work the Harkonnens did for him
Harkonnens have done his dirty work.
There are many secrets hidden in the shadow of Arrakis
In the shadows of Arrakis lie many secrets.
But perhaps the darkest of all is...
But the darkest of them all may remain...
The End of House Atreides
The end of House Atreides.
Dune Part 2
younger sister
Sister.
My father is dead
Father is dead.
Aren&#39;t you supposed to go back to Interstellar?
Shouldn&#39;t you go back to the stars?
together with him
Be with him.
I&#39;m afraid I don&#39;t have enough time
I&#39;m afraid I won&#39;t have enough time to
Take care of things before you come
fix things before you&#39;re coming.
This world is so cruel
This world is beyond cruelty.
enemy
Stay Here
Stay here.
Lower right
They are nearby
Did you hear that?
The rats are calling the sandworms
Sandworm!
Everyone, climb up quickly!
Watch for signs of sandworms
Safety
Turn on the shielding field!
There is no shielding field!
Where is the mouse running?
Never stand with your back to the enemy
Never stand with your back towards the opponent.
How many times have I told you?
How many times do I have to tell you that?
Are you OK?
You okay?
without
No.
How is she?
How about her?
she&#39;s fine
She&#39;s fine.
They don&#39;t usually go that deep.
They do not usually venture this deep.
They want to wipe out the Atreides.
They want to make sure no Atreides escaped.
You are too self-righteous
You think too much of yourself.
No, no, we are deep in the desert.
No, no, we are in the deep desert.
Only Fremen can survive here.
They are here for us, not for you.
They were here for us, not for you.
don’t worry
Don&#39;t worry.
I&#39;ll take you to a place they&#39;ll never find.
I&#39;m taking you somewhere they will never find us.
Dirty water
Filthy water.
It&#39;s full of chemicals, but
For cooling system can also
good enough for cooling system.
Don&#39;t spit it out
Don&#39;t let it out.
Are you OK?
You okay?
Don&#39;t spit it out
Don&#39;t let it out.
Almost
I can&#39;t.
I&#39;m fine
I&#39;m okay.
you sure?
Are you sure?
You played well
You fought well.
Once you wake up
Once you woke up.
I didn&#39;t sleep
I wasn&#39;t sleeping.
No No No
No, no, no.
Let me do it
I&#39;ll do it.
Arakkon Capital of Northern Arrakis
Mr. Laban
Lord Raban.
The spice fields are now safe
Now that the spice field is secured,
I strongly recommend that all troops
I strongly recommend bringing all troops
Evacuate Fremen territory
out of Fremen territories.
We lost too many men in the desert.
We&#39;re losing too many men to the desert
mouse
Rats.
What did you say?
I beg your pardon?
The people we lost...
We&#39;re losing them...
Gave it to the mouse
To rats.
Fremen
Fremen.
I can&#39;t confirm, sir.
I can&#39;t confirm, my Lord.
Communications are messy in the open sand
Communications are hectic in the open sands.
Your Task
Your orders,
Control the entire planet
were too controlling the whole of the planet.
We have……
We have–
This is only half
That&#39;s only half of it.
You may remember that the South is not a good place to live, sir.
As you may recall, the south is uninhabtable, my Lord
I suggest you take a break, okay?
May I suggest you get some rest?
mouse!
Rats!
Kill them all!
mouse!
Rats!
He asked us why we were late.
He&#39;s asking why we&#39;re so late.
He thinks you&#39;re spies.
You are not welcome here
He said……
He said...
I understood
I got that.
Thanks
Thanks.
Follow me
Stay close to me.
Tabur Caverns
Sietch Tabr
Jamie! Jamie!
You killed Jamie!
spy!
Witch!
Stop! Stop!
They don&#39;t know what they&#39;re talking about
Lisan al-Gheb! Lisan al-Gheb!
Savior!
I need your guidance on how to deal with those two foreigners.
Leave them to the desert
I saw the signs
here we go again
Stilgar, your faith has blinded you.
Lisan Al-Gheb wasn&#39;t even born yet!
He defeated Jamie in a fair fight.
He speaks our language
He will soon learn our way of survival
I would give my life for him
The desert will decide his fate
Where is that woman?
It seems that the Bene Gesserit&#39;s propaganda has penetrated into people&#39;s hearts.
Looks like the Bene Gesserit&#39;s &#39; propaganda has taken root
Some people already think I&#39;m their savior
Some of them already think I&#39;m their messiah.
Others think I am a false prophet.
Others, false prophet.
I have to convince those who don&#39;t believe
I must sway the non-believers.
If they follow me we can
If they follow me, we can
Disruption of spice production
disrupt spice production.
This is the only way I can get close to the emperor
That&#39;s the only way I can get to the emperor.
Your father didn&#39;t believe in revenge.
I believe
Hell, I do.
What&#39;s wrong?
What is happening?
Foreigners can’t eat spicy food?
what happened?
What is it?
Spices in food
There&#39;s spice in the food.
He must have beautiful blue eyes.
Don&#39;t laugh at him
He deserves our respect. He is a good fighter.
Woman, follow me
Woman, come with me.
Put it back in the well and our water is back.
We bless our brother, Jamie
38 million litres
38 million decaliters.
Even if we die of thirst
None of us, even dying of thirst
I won&#39;t drink this water.
would ever drink this water.
It is sacred
This is sacred.
Genesis Water
Genesis water.
We have thousands of these places.
We have thousands of places.
We have enough water
where we have enough water.
Lisan Al-Gheb will
The Lisan al-Gaib will
Changing the face of Arrakis
Change the face of Arrakis
It will bring back the trees. It will bring back the trees.
It will bring back trees, it will bring back...
Green Paradise Reappears
a green paradise.
So many souls
Never give your water to anyone else
Never give your water away,
Even the dead can&#39;t
not even for the dead.
Why did you show me this?
Why are you showing me this?
Because you are a Bene Gesserit.
Because You Are Bene Gesserit
Because you understand the prophecy
Because you understand the prophecies.
Lisan Al-Gheb&#39;s mother
The mother of the Lisan al-Gaib
Will become the Virgin Mary
will be a Reverend mother.
Our Lady is dying
Our Reverend Mother is dying.
You want me to take her place?
Yes
Yes,
I think
I do.
Do you believe Paul?
Do you believe in Paul?
There are signs
There are signs.
Yes
Yes.
What if I refuse?
What if I would refuse?
Then he is not Lisan Al-Gheb
Then he is not Lisan al-Gaib,
You won&#39;t have any meaning anymore.
And you have no purpose to serve.
So what else can you do?
What else is left to do then?
Put your water back into the well?
But return your water to the well?
It&#39;s an honor, isn&#39;t it?
I think you should feel honored.
This is a life or death decision
It was a choice between this or death,
So please forgive my disrespect
so forgive me if I&#39;m not flattered.
How does one become a Madonna?
How does one become a Reverend Mother?
Different cultures are different
It&#39;s different from one culture to another.
On Arrakis I don&#39;t know
Here on Arrakis, I have no idea.
You are scared
You&#39;re afraid.
Our Lady carries
A Reverend Mother has the task
Preserve the Virgin Mary of their past generations
of holding the memories
The mission of all memories
of all the Reverend Mothers that came before them,
So I will be given centuries of pain and sorrow
so I&#39;ll be given centuries of pain and sorrow.
Is it dangerous?
Fatal to men
It&#39;s lethal for men.
Absolutely
That&#39;s for sure.
What are you laughing at?
What are you guys laughing about?
Never mind
Don&#39;t bother.
You don&#39;t believe all this?
You don&#39;t believe in all this?
No, we don&#39;t believe it.
No, we don&#39;t.
These are the beliefs of the South.
These are all Southern beliefs.
Southern faith?
Southern beliefs?
Southern tribes believe in the Messiah
Southern tribes believe that a Messiah
Will come to save us from evil
will come to deliver us from evil.
You don&#39;t believe in Lisan Al-Gheb?
You don&#39;t believe in the Lisan al-Gaib?
We trust the Fremen
We believe in Fremen
Amen
Do you want to control others?
You want to control people?
You tell them the savior is coming
You tell them a Messiah will come.
Then they would wait for centuries.
Then they&#39;ll wait, for centuries.
Now we must pray
Now, we must pray.
What&#39;s up with him?
What about him?
Stilgar?
He is from the South
He&#39;s from the South.
You didn&#39;t notice his accent.
What will happen to my mother?
What&#39;ll happen to my mother?
She drinks sandworm urine
It is not funny
He&#39;s going to lose her.
If she&#39;s stupid enough to drink poison
shut up! shut up!
We are praying
This is the water of life
It liberates the mind
If you drink
You will die
You can see
drink!
What&#39;s this?
What did we do?
She is pregnant
That&#39;s not a miracle!
You saw it with your own eyes!
Lisan Al-Gheb&#39;s mother
Will survive the holy poison trial
She did it
Just like it&#39;s written in the book!
That was written by her people!
Blasphemy
The prophecy has come true
The savior must be a Fremen!
Arrakis must be liberated by its own people!
She&#39;s right. She&#39;s right.
She&#39;s right.
This is not a miracle
It&#39;s no miracle.
My mother was trained in this area.
My mother was trained to do that.
Convert toxins into something else
Poison transmutation is something
A high-ranking Bene Gesserit can do
Advanced Bene Gesserit can do.
I am not the savior
I&#39;m not the Mahdi.
I&#39;m not here to lead.
I&#39;m here to learn your way of survival.
I&#39;m here to fight with you
I&#39;m here to fight beside you.
That&#39;s my only request
That&#39;s all I&#39;m asking.
I humbly say he is the savior
All the more reason to believe he is!
Just like it&#39;s written in the book!
how is she?
How is she?
She&#39;s scared, but she&#39;s okay.
She was frightened but she&#39;s okay.
She talks to me
She talks to me.
She believes you
She believes in you.
she says
She says
Kwisatz Haderach shows us the way
You&#39;re almost there
You&#39;re so close now.
Only one step away
Only one step remains.
You will become Kwisatz Haderak
you will become the Kwisatz Haderach.
Only one step away
Only one step remains.
You have to be like me
You must do what I did.
You must drink the water of life
You must drink the water of life.
You will free your mind and you will see
Your mind is gonna open and you will see.
You will see!
Beauty and terror!
If you want to fight with us
If you want to fight with us,
First you must learn
first thing you must learn
Blending with the desert
to be one with the desert.
There are tents and enough food.
So here is a tent and enough food.
I want you to walk to that little sand dune and then back.
I want you to cross that small erg and come back.
Come back at night
Come by night.
Do you know how to use a compass?
You know how to use a paracompass.
Will do
Yes.
Is there anything else I need to know?
Anything else I should know?
Except for the sandworms and the Harkonnens
Beside the worms and the Harkonnens,
Beware of Earth Spiders
beware of the trap door spiders.
Centipedes are annoying too.
Centipedes are very nasty.
Not the big ones.
Big and harmless
They are harmless.
But you have to be careful, little one.
But the little ones you have to worry about.
Don&#39;t listen to the giant.
Don&#39;t ever, ever listen to the Djinn.
Djinn
The Djinn.
Djinn Desert Soul
Djinn, desert spirits.
They whispered in the night
They whisper at night.
They will charm you
They can possess you.
Really, be careful.
They are demons
They are demons.
But it’s true
But it&#39;s true.
Don&#39;t listen to them.
He didn&#39;t know how to cross the sand.
Stilgar will kill him.
What does he want to prove?
What do you think?
“A Prophet Knows the Way in the Desert”
I think this is best
Is it this way?
Do you care about him now?
He is different from other strangers.
He is sincere
Jamie
Jamis
You walk like a drunk lizard
You sand walk like a drunk lizard.
Really? So far I&#39;m doing pretty good.
Yeah, I&#39;m doing pretty good so far.
We haven&#39;t entered the sandworm&#39;s territory yet.
We&#39;re not even in worm territory yet.
You have to break your rhythm
You have to break up your rhythm.
like this
Like this.
It&#39;s interesting because in the film book
Now that&#39;s interesting because in the film books
I&#39;ve studied anthropologists who say
I&#39;ve studied, the anthropologists say in order
You have to follow certain rules to walk on the sand.
to properly sand walk, you actually have to.
never mind
Nevermind.
please continue
Please keep going.
You know I&#39;m the only one who believes
You know, I&#39;m the only one who believes
You&#39;ll last till summer.
you&#39;re gonna make it until summer.
If you want to follow us in the desert
If you wanna follow us in the desert,
You need to know the principle of wind catcher
you need to know how wind traps work.
So listen to me
So listen to me.
I always think it&#39;s simple
It&#39;s always neat to me.
They are simple but require constant attention
They&#39;re simple, but they require constant attention.
What?
Don&#39;t look at me like that
Stop looking at me like that.
you&#39;re right
You&#39;re right.
If we want to protect your brother
If we want to protect your brother,
We need all Fremen to believe the prophecy.
We need all the Fremen to believe in the prophecy.
We must convert unbelievers one by one
We must convert the non-believers one by one.
We have to start with the weak.
We need to start with the weaker ones.
Weak-willed person
the vulnerable ones.
Those who are afraid of us
The ones that fear us.
Chinnie!
Chani!
Reloading
Reload.
The shield is only closed when the helicopter is firing.
The shield. They only open when they&#39;re firing.
I know
I know that.
What do you think I&#39;m doing?
What do you think I&#39;m trying to do?
I&#39;m the lead
I&#39;m triggering.
Wait for my signal
On my signal.
Prepare
Be ready.
Oh damn.
Oh shit.
You saw what he did
He had expected it.
He saved her life
He saw
He can foresee
Muad&#39;Dib likes his taste
Who taught you to fight like this?
Who taught you to fight like that?
My former master
My old masters.
They are very good friends.
And they were close friends.
They were massacred along with my father.
They were a massacre. Alongside my father.
You have been fighting the Harkonnens for decades.
You&#39;ve been fighting The Harkonnens for decades.
My family has fought them for centuries.
My family has been fighting them for centuries.
I know their habits and their way of thinking.
Their habits, their ways of thinking. I know everything about them,
You know the desert well.
You know everything about the desert.
You harness the power of the desert
You harness the very power of it.
Together we can stop them
We can stop them together.
Let them die without losing their lives
Bury them in the sand where they belong.
Make this planet yours again
So that this planet can be yours once more.
What do you want us to do?
What will you have us do?
What would you do, Stilgar?
I will march north
I would strike even further north.
Then I will march north
Then I will go further north.
The further north you go
The further north you go,
You are more likely to die
the more likely it is you die.
I will die
Maybe you will die too
But others will move on
They will not stop until the Fremen are free.
He should join the Fremen Death Squad
He needs a name, Stilgar.
Bravo! Bravo!
I see strength in you
I see strength in you.
Like Youso
Meaning &quot;base of the beam&quot;
Come here Come here
Come, come.
Among us, you should be called Youso
You shall be known among us as Usul.
Friends
Usul.
Now, you join the Fremen Death Squad and become a warrior
And now a Fedaykin is a fighter.
You must also choose one
and needs a war name.
Battle name
You must choose.
What do you call this little desert mouse?
How do you call the small desert mouse again?
Muad&#39;Dib Muad&#39;Dib
Muad&#39;Dib.
No No No
No, no, no.
Oh no, Muad&#39;Dib is very smart.
Oh no, Muad&#39;Dib is wise.
Muad&#39;Dib knew how to survive in the desert
Muad&#39;dib is wise in the ways of the desert.
Muad&#39;Dib can make his own water
Muad&#39;Dib creates his own water.
Ability to identify the constellations pointing north
The constellation that points to the North
So we call it Muad&#39;Dib
We call Muad&#39;Dib.
The person who gives direction
The one who points the way.
This name is powerful.
That is a powerful name.
Now you are our brother.
Paul Moadib Youssou
Paul Muad&#39;Dib Usul.
Hey! Stilgar!
Father, I found my way.
So beautiful
It&#39;s breathtaking.
Look, this is the spice.
Look, right there&#39;s spice
Whenever the sun sets, Arrakis is particularly beautiful.
Arrakis is so beautiful when the sun is low.
In your hometown
Where you&#39;re from...
Did water really fall from the sky?
Does water really fall from the sky?
Oh yes
Oh, yes.
Sometimes it rains for a week in Caladan
Sometimes it rains for a few weeks, in Caladan
Look at the sand here, imagine it&#39;s all water
Where you see sand here, imagine water.
Our castle stands on a cliff by the sea.
Our castle stands on cliffs, over the sea.
Even if you dive in, you can&#39;t reach the bottom.
If you dive in, you can&#39;t reach the bottom.
Did you jump in?
You dive in?
Yes
Yes.
This is called swimming
It&#39;s called swimming.
I don&#39;t believe it, Youso
I don&#39;t believe you, Usul.